A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Penitentiary, 1796-1991 (bulk 1906-1970)
Library of Virginia
- Series IV. Office of the Superintendent, 1869-1991 (bulk 1908-1970)., Extent: 76.60 cubic feet of records and 19 volumes. (Box 391-572, 693 and Oversize Box 2., Volume 143-161.)
  - Series IV. Subseries B. General Correspondence, 1892-1991 (bulk 1908-1970). (Box 391-484.)
    - Series IV.B.VI. Superintendent's Files, 1934-1990 (bulk 1940-1970). (Box 454-477 and Oversize Box 2.)
      - Jailmen
        - Jail Prisoners Released from Hospital, 1970. (Box 476, Folder 3)
        - Jail Prisoners Released from Hospital, 1970. (Box 476, Folder 4)
        - Jail Prisoners Released from Hospital, 1970. (Box 476, Folder 5)
      - War Files
        - American Prison Association, Committee on Post-War Planning, 1944-1945. (Box 477, Folder 1)
        - Burke, W.H. (Major) C.M.P., Chief, Prison Industries Branch WPD, 1941-1944. (Box 477, Folder 2)
        - Correspondence, 1941-1943. (Box 477, Folder 3)
      - State Farm, 1956-1973. (Box 477, Folder 4)
      - General Correspondence, 1912-1963. (Box 477, Folder 5)
      - Maximum Security Building, Specifications, Virginia State Penitentiary, Commission No. 1236, Carneal and Johnston, 25 January 1950. (Box 477, Folder 6)
      - Superintendent's Correspondence, Binders
        - Reference Material and undated. (Box 477, Folder 7)
        - 1943-1990. (Box 477, Folder 8)
    - Series IV.B.VII. Commissioner of Public Welfare Files, 1924-1947. (Box 478.)
      Correspondence are housed in one box. Subjects include: Charter, Prisoner Association, Industrial Schools; Jonathan Bryan Bequest to the Industrial Schools; Children's Bureau Receiving Home; and Receiving Home Property.
      - Charter, Prisoner Association, Industrial Schools, 1924-1941. (Box 478, Folder 1)
      - The Jonathan Bryan Bequest to the Industrial Schools, 1934-1947. (Box 478, Folder 2)
      - Children's Bureau Receiving Home, 1933-1937. (Box 478, Folder 3)
      - Receiving Home Property, 1943-1947. (Box 478, Folder 4)
    - Series IV.B.VIII. Warden Raymond M. Muncy, 1987-1991. (Box 479-484.)
      Warden Raymond M. Muncy's records are housed in six boxes and are further divided into Execution Files, Photographs and Videotapes, and Reports and Correspondence. The Execution Files are restricted for 50 years from date of execution. There are execution files for Richard Lee Whitley (executed 6 July 1987), Earl Clanton, Jr. (executed 14 April 1988), Alton Wayne (executed 30 August 1989), Richard Thomas Boggs (executed 19 July 1990), Wilbert Lee Evans (executed 17 October 1990) and Buddy Earl Justus (executed 13 December 1990) (b479). Each execution file contains a photograph taken prior to execution, list of visitors, list of witnesses to execution and an autopsy report. In addition, there are audio cassette narrations for the executions of Whitley, Wayne, Boggs and Evans (b480). On these recordings, an unidentified Dept. of Corrections employee provides an eye-witness narration of the execution. It is unknown why these recordings were made. Other notable records include: photographs of aftermath of 9 January 1983 riot at Virginia State Penitentiary (b481, f1); photographs of Penitentiary and Death House, 1991 (b481, f2); videotape of closing of Virginia State Penitentiary ceremony, 14 December 1990 (b481, f3); Research Report "Special Housing Unit Officer Study: Death Row and Death Watch Officers", 1989 (b481, f8); and copies of "Penitentiary Employees' News, 1989-1990 (b481, f9).
      - Execution Files (Restricted for 50 years from date of execution)
        - Execution (Box 479, Folder 1)
        - Richard Lee Whitley, 124625, executed 6 July 1987. (Box 479, Folder 2)
        - Earl Clanton, Jr., 123635 executed 14 April 1988. (Box 479, Folder 3)
        - Alton Wayne, 115422, executed 30 August 1989. (Box 479, Folder 4)
        - Richard Thomas Boggs, 139430, executed 19 July 1990. (Box 479, Folder 5)
        - Wilbert Lee Evans, 124549, executed 17 October 1990. (Box 479, Folder 6)
        - Buddy Earl Justus, 117767, executed 13 December 1990. (Box 479, Folder 7)
        - Cassette Tape narrating execution of Richard Lee Whitley, 124625, executed 6 July 1987 (Box 480)
        - Cassette Tape narrating execution of Alton Wayne, 115422, executed 30 August 1989 (Box 480)
        - Cassette Tape narrating execution of Richard Thomas Boggs, 139430, executed 19 July 1990 (Box 480)
        - Cassette Tape narrating execution of Wilbert Lee Evans, 124549, executed 17 October 1990 (Box 480)
      - Photographs and Videotapes
        - Photographs of aftermath of 9 January 1983 riot at Virginia State Penitentiary along with newspaper articles and unidentified photographs of guards, 1983. (Box 481, Folder 1)
        - Photographs of Penitentiary, Death House and Demolition of Penitentiary, 1991. (Box 481, Folder 2)
        - Videotape (VHS) of Closing of Virginia State Penitentiary Ceremony, 14 December 1990. (Box 481, Folder 3)
        - Videotape (VHS) of news magazine segment on capital punishment, includes interview with Raymond Muncy, November 1988. (Box 481, Folder 4)
        - Oversize Pictures of Virginia State Penitentiary and Surrounding Area, 1904, 1909, 1932, 1971 and undated. (Box 482, Folder 1)
      - Reports and Correspondence
        - List of Superintendents and copies of historic correspondence and newspaper articles, 1916-1990. (Box 481, Folder 5)
        - "The Riot as a Psychological Study: Analysis and Implications" by Thomas Kirk, 1974. (Box 481, Folder 6)
        - "A Brief History of the Virginia State Penitentiary" by James M. Good, December 1973. (Box 481, Folder 7)
        - "Special Housing Unit Officer Study: Death Row and Death Watch Officers" by Robert Johnson, 30 May 1989. (Box 481, Folder 8)
        - Copies of Penitentiary Employees' News, January 1989-December 1990. (Box 481, Folder 9)
        - Comprehensive Plan to Close the Virginia State Penitentiary, 1990-1991. (Box 481, Folder 10)
      - Front Gate Sign-In Log Book (volume), 24 April 1990-1 March 1991. (Box 483)
      - Penitentiary Ephemera (including keys to electric chair) (Box 484)
  - Series IV. Subseries C: State Convict Road Force, )1906-1940. (Box 485-532.)
    This subseries is housed in 48 boxes and arranged chronologically. The filing arrangement within each time period varies; alphabetical by correspondent or subject, a numbering system or by camp number (and by reverse chronological order therein). This subseries contains correspondence between the Superintendent and/or Assistant Superintendent in charge of the State Convict Road Force and the Clerk of the State Convict Road Force and/or camp sergeants. Researchers should note that additional State Convict Road Force records can be found in Series V. This subseries details the operations and conditions found in State Convict Road Force camps.
    The State Convict Road Force was created by the General Assembly in 1906 as part of the Withers-Lassiter "good roads" law that created the State Highway Commission. The Penitentiary was responsible for creating, administrating and supplying mobile convict road camps for use by the Highway Commission The camps were manned by felons from the Penitentiary and by misdeamants from local jails. The number and location of camps changed based upon the needs of the State Highway Commission. The Penitentiary Superintendent and/or Assistant Penitentiary Superintendent was head of the State Convict Road Force. He was assisted by a chief clerk.
    Subjects include: supply orders for camps, bills for supplies, contracts for supplies, requests for employment as guards on State Convict Road Force, hiring guards, reports from camp Sergeants, prisoner discipline, prisoner escapes and escape attempts, prisoner injuries, transportation of prisoners to camps, discipline of guards, resignation and transfer of camp Sergeants, location and movement of camps and camp conditions (including the impact of the 1918-1919 Influenza Pandemic).
    Notable records from 1906-1907 include: correspondence between Supt. E.F. Morgan and Robert Catlett, assistant to the Attorney General on the disposition of the bodies of jail men who die while on the State Convict Road Force, August 1906 (b485, f1); and correspondence from Sgt. W.B. Pattie, at camp near Williamsburg, describing the escape of a one legged Italian jail man (b485, f2).
    The 1916-1917 records are arranged by assigned number. For a partial index see b510, f2. Notable documents include: No. 497 - Death of Dorsey Coles, No. 13529, Camp 11, died 18 March 1916 includes Transportation of Corpse form, body shipped to Anatomical Board, Medical College of Virginia (b502, f2); No. 1075 - establishment of convict camp at Catawba Sanatorium, 28 July 1916 (b504, f1); No. 2424 - list of guards on the State Convict Road Force who are eligible to get bonus for 24 and 12 months continuous satisfactory service, 1917 (b507, f1); No. 2608 - report on State Convict Road Force for Commission on Economy and Efficiency, 11 April 1917 (b507, f6); and No. 3315 - deed of lease for camp site, 13 October 1917 (b509, f4).
    The 1917-1919 correspondence are arranged by camp number and reverse chronological order therein. This group of records documents the toll the 1918-1919 Influenza Pandemic had on the State Convict Road Force camps. Notable records include: Camp 2: Sgt. H.B.T. Coleman sick with influenza, 29 October 1918, 4 November 1918, 9 November 1918, (b510, f4); Camp 4: William Lowry, 14485, died of influenza and pneumonia, letters from Lowry's mother, Mrs. Isabella Ruffin, about shipping his body, 18 February 1919 (b511, f1); and reports on influenza in camp, 20 January 1919, 18 January 1919, 15 January 1919, 11 January 1919, 10 January 1919, 10 January 1919, 8 January 1919, 2 January 1919 (b511, f1); Camp 5: Sgt. Stanley letters on influenza in camp, 25 January 1919; Stanley takes over camp from Sgt. H.B. Shepherd, 7 December and 9 December 1918; Sgt. Shepherd's wife and children have influenza and requests to leave camp, 5 December 1918; Shepherd takes over camp, 16 November 1918; Sgt. R.D. Hockler resigns, 23 October 1918; and Sgt. R.E. Mitchell resigns, 19 September 1918, 11 September 1918 and 28 June 1918 (all b511, f3); Camp 7: influenza, 8 November 1918, 6 November 1918 (b511, f5); Camp 8: influenza, 1 November 1918, 29 October 1918, 25 October 1918, 22 October 1918, 15 October 1918 (b511, f6); Camp 10: influenza in camp/deaths, 5 December 1918, 2 December 1918, 30 November 1918, 27 November 1918, 29 October 1918; staffing difficulties because of labor shortage, 7 August 1918; and condition of camp, 18 May 1918 (b512, f3); Camp 11: correspondence between Mrs. T.E. Rogers, widow of Sgt. Rogers and Supt. Wood, 11 January 1919, 10 January 1919; and influenza in camp/death of Sgt. Rogers, December 1918 (b512, f4); Camp 12: death of George Everett, 13702, from influenza, 27 December 1918; three influenza deaths, 17 December 1918; influenza in camp, 17 December 1918, 9 December 1918, 11 December 1918, 5 December 1918; Camp 15: death of John Walker, 14528, from flu, 21 April 1919; influenza in camp, 6 February 1919, 30 January 1919, 28 January 1919, 27 January 1919, 25 January 1919, 24 January 1919, 22 January1919, 21 January 1919, and 19 January 1919; and L.H. Jones offered position of Assistant Superintendent, 18 September 1918 (all b513, f5); Camp 19: influenza in camp, 13 November 1918 (b514, f6); George Sears, 11901, escape attempt and death, 20 January 1919, 17 November 1918, 15 November 1918, 1 November 1918, 26 October 1918, 24 October 1918 (b514, f6); death of Charles Burwell, 14448, shot while trying to escape,13 March 1918 (b515, f1); and flood at camp, 2 February 1918 (b515, f1); Camp 20: influenza in camp, 14 December 1918, 12 December 1918, 11 December 1918, 2 December 1918, 29 October 1918, 18 October 1918 (b515, f2); Camp 23: report on murder of Harry Brown, 15050, by Hike Perry, 14206, 21 December 1918 (b515, f5); Wood describes influenza cases within his family and quarantine at Virginia. Penitentiary, 17 October 1918 (b515, f5); Sgt. Cook accused of not feeding prisoners properly, 22 February 1918 (b515, f5); and Cook's resignation, 20 February 1918 (b515, f5); Camp 28: influenza in camp, 9 December 1918, 6 December 1918, 2 December 1918, (b516, f6); Camp 30: George Bolling, 13845, shot and killed in self-defense by guard, 5 April 1919, (b517, f3); influenza in camp, 31 January 1919, 28 January 1919, 28 January 1919, 27 January 1919, 25 January 1919, 24 January 1919, 16 January 1919, 11 January 1919, (b517, f3); Camp 31: resignation of Sgt. Wade, 26 April 1919 (b517, f5); and influenza in camp, 10 February 1919, 30 January 1919, 28 January 1919, 23 January 1919, 20 January 1919, 15 January 1919 (b517, f5); Camp 32: resignation of Sgt. E.J. Griffith, camp turned over to E.R. Parker, 12 November 1918, 8 November 1918 (b518, f2); resignation of Anderson, Griffith takes over camp, 17 October 1918, 14 October 1918, 27 September 1918 (b518, f2); and resignation of Sgt. Harris, replaced by Anderson, 6 September 1918, 9 August 1918 (b518, f2); Camp 33: influenza in camp, 27 December 1918, 19 December 1918, 18 December 1918, 12 December 1918 (b518, f3); G.W. Earman takes charge of camp, 23 September 1918 (b518, f3); Earman and Van Snellings swapped camps, 16 September 1918, 11 September 1918, 6 September 1918 (b518, f3).
    Only a small portion of the 1922-1927 correspondence are extant (camps 22-32). Notable correspondence include: Camp 24: letter from Sgt. W.W. Higginbotham to Supt. R.M. Youell, 13 November 1924, containing Higginbotham's response to complaints received by Governor's Office that Higginbotham was mistreating prisoners (b521, f2); Camp 30: Sgt. R.M. Reames discharged for drinking, 27 August 1925 and 23 June 1925 (b523, f1); underground letters to governor complaining about treatment, 20 January 1925 (b523, f1); deportation of John Field and Otto Larsen, 15 September 1924 (b523, f2); complaints about camp, escapes, etc. 3 April 1923 (b523, f2); and Sgt. E.B. Anderson replaced at the request of the State Highway Department, 8 August 1922 (b523, f3).
    The 1932-1934 correspondence between the Superintendent and Camp Sergeants contain records related to prisoner issues such as health, discipline, "good time" and date of discharge. Notable correspondence include: Camp 6: Paul Trent, 30985, attempted suicide by cutting his throat with a safety razor blade after learning his wife filed for divorce; he survived, 30 December 1933 (b526, f6); and SuperintendentYouell to Sgt. W.T. Reames warning him that he was nearly fired after the "Scott County trouble", 1 February 1933 - see also 30 April 1931 (b526, f6); Camp 8: Homer Smith, 30678, attempted suicide by cutting himself with a razor blade; he survived, 20 November 1933 (b526, f8); and Eugene W. Potts, 26362, request for restoration of good conduct time; describes his escapes and camp transfers, 1 December 1932 (b526, f8); Camp 11: Harry Smith, 25207, request for transfer/complaints about camp conditions and disciplined by Sgt., 9 January 1934, 26 June 1933 (b527, f1) and 9 December 1932, 23 October 1932, 29 September 1932, 29 July 1932, 23 July 1932, 20 July 1932, 15 July 1932 (b527, f2); Camp 15: Sgt. M.C. Russell described a drunken disturbance involving four prisoners, 16 February 1934 (b527, f6); punishment and shooting of Willie Williams, 17280, by Sgt. M.C. Russell, 1 February 1934, 3 January 1934, 16 December 1933 (b527, f6); and James Bell, 24204, lost an eye when hit by a rock, 23 April 1933 (b527, f6).
    - 1906-1907
      - Abingdon Grocery Company - Sarah Jones. (Box 485, Folder 1)
      - Charles T. Lassiter - Sgt. W.P. Tatum. (Box 485, Folder 2)
      - Sgt. W.P. Tatum - J.E. Vines. (Box 485, Folder 3)
      - J.E. Vines - G.W. Zirkle. (Box 485, Folder 4)
    - 1907-1908
      - Employment Applications],. (Box 485, Folder 5)
      - Orders/Supplies], 1908. (Box 485, Folder 6)
      - [Payrolls], 1908. (Box 485, Folder 7)
      - Prisoners], 1908. (Box 485, Folder 8)
      - [Railroad File], 1908. (Box 485, Folder 9)
      - [Stove File], 1908. (Box 485, Folder 10)
      - Scrapbook of Newspaper Clippings (volume), 1906-1908, 1910. (Box 486)
    - 1908-1909
      - No. 1 - Camp Equipment, Free Transportation of. (Box 487, Folder 1)
      - No. 2 - Bills (part one). (Box 487, Folder 2)
      - No. 2 - Bills (part two). (Box 487, Folder 3)
      - No. 3 - Orders, Camp No. 1. (Box 487, Folder 4)
      - No. 4 - Orders, Camp No. 2. (Box 487, Folder 5)
      - No. 5 - Orders, Camp No. 3. (Box 487, Folder 6)
      - No. 6 - Orders, Camp No. 4. (Box 487, Folder 7)
      - No. 7 - Orders, Camp No. 5. (Box 487, Folder 8)
      - No. 8 - Orders, Camp No. 6. (Box 487, Folder 9)
      - No. 9 - Orders, Camp No. 7. (Box 488, Folder 1)
      - No. 10 - Orders, Camp No. 8. (Box 488, Folder 2)
      - No. 11 - Orders, Camp No. 9. (Box 488, Folder 3)
      - No. 12 - Orders, Camp No. 10. (Box 488, Folder 4)
      - No. 13 - Orders, Camp No. 11. (Box 488, Folder 5)
      - No. 14 - Orders, Camp No. 12. (Box 488, Folder 6)
      - No. 14 1/4 - Orders, Camp No. 13. (Box 488, Folder 7)
      - No. 14 1/2 - Orders, Camp No. 14. (Box 488, Folder 8)
      - No. 15 - [Terms of Prisoners], Jailmen. (Box 488, Folder 9)
      - No. 16 - Contingent. (Box 488, Folder 10)
      - No. 17 - Jailmen, Securing of, 29 December 1909 to 1 November 1909. (Box 489, Folder 1)
      - No. 17 - Jailmen, Securing of, 30 October 1909 to 25 September 1909. (Box 489, Folder 2)
      - No. 17 - Jailmen, Securing of, 24 September 1909 to 31 August 1909. (Box 489, Folder 3)
      - No. 17 - Jailmen, Securing of, 30 August 1909 to 17 August 1909. (Box 489, Folder 4)
      - No. 17 - Jailmen, Securing of, 16 August 1909 to 1 July 1909. (Box 489, Folder 5)
      - No. 17 - Jailmen, Securing of, 30 June 1909 to 25 May 1909. (Box 489, Folder 6)
      - No. 17 - Jailmen, Securing of, 24 May 1909 to 7 April 1909. (Box 490, Folder 1)
      - No. 17 - Jailmen, Securing of, 5 April 1909 to 10 March 1909. (Box 490, Folder 2)
      - No. 17 - Jailmen, Securing of, 6 February 1909 to 1 December 1908. (Box 490, Folder 3)
      - No. 17 - Jailmen, Securing of, 27 November 1908 to 1 October 1908. (Box 490, Folder 4)
      - No. 18 - [Application for Positions]. (Box 490, Folder 5)
      - No. 19 - Report of Camps (part one). (Box 490, Folder 6)
      - No. 19 - Report of Camps (part one). (Box 490, Folder 7)
      - No. 19 - Report of Camps (part three). (Box 491, Folder 1)
      - No. 19 - Report of Camps (part four). (Box 491, Folder 2)
      - No. 20 - Condition of Men at Camps. (Box 491, Folder 3)
      - No. 21 - Roofing, Lumber, Furlough. (Box 491, Folder 4)
      - No. 22 - Furnishing Men to Contractors and Camps. (Box 491, Folder 5)
      - No. 23 - Assaulting of Guards. (Box 491, Folder 6)
      - No. 24 - Pardons. (Box 491, Folder 7)
      - No. 25 - Where Abouts of Men. (Box 491, Folder 8)
      - No. 26 - Contracts. (Box 491, Folder 9)
      - No. 27 - Stolen Shot Gun. (Box 491, Folder 10)
      - No. 28 - Prisoners Board Account. (Box 491, Folder 11)
      - No. 29 - [Camps, Moving and Transferring of Men] (part one). (Box 492, Folder 1)
      - No. 29 - [Camps, Moving and Transferring of Men] (part two). (Box 492, Folder 2)
      - No. 29 - [Camps, Moving and Transferring of Men] (part three). (Box 492, Folder 3)
      - No. 29 - [Camps, Moving and Transferring of Men] (part four). (Box 492, Folder 4)
      - [No. 30 - Missing]
      - No. 31 - [Transportation Certificates, Discharged Men]. (Box 492, Folder 5)
      - [No. 32 to No. 37 - Missing]
      - No. 38 - [Escaped Prisoners]. (Box 492, Folder 6)
      - [No. 39 to No. 42 - Missing]
      - No. 43 - [Record]. (Box 492, Folder 7)
      - [No. Number - Supplies Shipped to Camps]. (Box 492, Folder 8)
    - 1910
      - Camp No. 1 (part one). (Box 493, Folder 1)
      - Camp No. 1 (part two). (Box 493, Folder 2)
      - Camp No. 2 (part one). (Box 493, Folder 3)
      - Camp No. 2 (part two). (Box 493, Folder 4)
      - [Camp No. 3 - Missing]
      - Camp No. 4. (Box 493, Folder 5)
      - Camp No. 5 (part one). (Box 493, Folder 6)
      - Camp No. 5 (part two). (Box 494, Folder 1)
      - Camp No. 6. (Box 494, Folder 2)
      - Camp No. 7. (Box 494, Folder 3)
      - Camp No. 8. (Box 494, Folder 4)
      - [Camp No. 9 - Missing]
      - Camp No. 10 (part one). (Box 494, Folder 5)
      - Camp No. 10 (part two). (Box 494, Folder 6)
      - Camp No. 11 (part one). (Box 495, Folder 1)
      - Camp No. 11 (part two). (Box 495, Folder 2)
      - Camp No. 12 (part one). (Box 495, Folder 3)
      - Camp No. 12 (part two). (Box 495, Folder 4)
      - Camp No. 13 (part one). (Box 495, Folder 5)
      - Camp No. 13 (part two). (Box 495, Folder 6)
      - Camp No. 14. (Box 495, Folder 7)
      - General Files, 31 December 1910 to 8 September 1910. (Box 496, Folder 1)
      - General Files, 6 September 1910 to 1 July 1910. (Box 496, Folder 2)
      - General Files, 30 June 1910 to 27 April 1910. (Box 496, Folder 3)
      - General Files, 25 April 1910 to 15 March 1910. (Box 496, Folder 4)
      - General Files, 14 March 1910 to 1 January 1910 (with a few letters from 1909). (Box 496, Folder 5)
      - Proposals for Supplies, Quarter Ending 31 December 1910. (Box 497, Folder 1)
      - Small Pox File (Camp No. 5, Russell County), 1910. (Box 497, Folder 2)
      - Feeding Prisoners at Vines' Camp, Augusta County (Camp 2), 1909-1910. (Box 497, Folder 3)
      - Coal, 1910. (Box 497, Folder 4)
    - 1911
      - Camp No. 1, 31 July 1911 to 31 December 1910. (Box 497, Folder 5)
      - Camp No. 1 - No. 15, August 1911. (Box 497, Folder 6)
      - General Files, 15 August 1911 to 21 May 1911. (Box 498, Folder 1)
      - General Files, 20 May 1911 to 17 March 1911. (Box 498, Folder 2)
      - General Files, 14 March 1911 to 3 January 1911. (Box 498, Folder 3)
      - Discharge Lists, 1911. (Box 498, Folder 4)
      - Summer Clothing, 1911. (Box 498, Folder 5)
    - 1912-1913
      - Recapture of Cornelius Davis, No. 9088, 1912. (Box 498, Folder 6)
      - Camp 4 (Sgt. H.H. Spangler), 1913. (Box 498, Folder 7)
      - Camp 4 (Sgt. H.H. Spangler), 1913. (Box 499, Folder 1)
      - Camp 4 (Sgt. H.H. Spangler), 1912. (Box 499, Folder 2)
      - [Prisoner Discharge], 1913. (Box 499, Folder 3)
      - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1913. (Box 499, Folder 3a)
      - List of Successful Bidders for Camp Supplies (volume), December 1913. (Box 499, Folder 4)
    - 1914-1915
      - Camp 3, 1915. (Box 499, Folder 5)
      - Camp 7, 1915. (Box 499, Folder 6)
      - Camp 9, 1916. (Box 499, Folder 7)
      - Unidentified Camp, 1915. (Box 499, Folder 8)
      - Camp 33 (Sgt. J.W. Woodland), 1915. (Box 499, Folder 9)
      - Contracts for the Quarter ending 30 June 1915. (Box 499, Folder 10)
      - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1915. (Box 499, Folder 11)
      - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1914-1915. (Box 500, Folder 1)
    - Camp Supplies, 1914-1917
      - Clothing, 1915. (Box 500, Folder 2)
      - Clothing, 1917. (Box 500, Folder 3)
      - Clothing, Camp 3 (Chesterfield County), 1914-1917. (Box 500, Folder 4)
      - Coal, 1914. (Box 500, Folder 5)
      - Coal, 1915. (Box 500, Folder 6)
      - Coal, 1916. (Box 500, Folder 7)
      - Shoes, 1914-1915. (Box 500, Folder 8)
      - Shoes, 1916. (Box 500, Folder 9)
      - Shoes, 1917. (Box 500, Folder 10)
    - 1916-1917
      - State Convict Road Force, No. 201 - No. 241. (Box 501, Folder 1)
      - State Convict Road Force, No. 242 - No. 274. (Box 501, Folder 2)
      - State Convict Road Force, No. 275 - No. 300. (Box 501, Folder 3)
      - State Convict Road Force, No. 301 - No. 349 [No. 310- 311 missing]. (Box 501, Folder 4)
      - State Convict Road Force, No. 350 - No. 399. (Box 501, Folder 5)